When I was really little back in the early 90s my dad had an old word processor an old word processor
90 年代初我很小的时候，我爸爸有一个旧的文字处理器一个旧的文字处理器
word processor is what Microsoft Word is it's basically something that you would use just for writing.
字处理器就是Microsoft Word，它基本上是您仅用于写作的东西。
But it was a whole computer only for that.
但这只是一台完整的计算机。
My dad had an old word processor and it could only do one thing process words.
我爸爸有一个旧的文字处理器，它只能做一件事来处理文字。
It had no games and so I wasn't interested at all.
它没有游戏，所以我一点也不感兴趣。
OK.
好的。
Try sharing my emotions trying to share my feeling about this thing.
试着分享我的情绪，试着分享我对这件事的感受。
Back then most computers were similar to that very simple no games no fun.
那时候大部分的电脑都类似于那种很简单的没有游戏没有乐趣。
A few years later though our family got a brand new computer with Windows 95 Windows 95 and that had
几年后，虽然我们家得到了一台装有 Windows 95 Windows 95 的全新电脑，而且
way more functionality that could do much more.
更多的功能可以做更多的事情。
It could it could do many many more things.
它可以做更多的事情。
It had a color screen games and mass paint and it could even play videos.
它有彩屏游戏和大量绘画，甚至可以播放视频。
It could even play videos but no internet.
它甚至可以播放视频，但不能上网。
It could also say it had no Internet there was no Internet.
它也可以说它没有互联网就没有互联网。
It totally blew my mind at first.
起初它完全让我大吃一惊。
It means something so amazing or so crazy you can't believe it.
这意味着一些如此惊人或如此疯狂的事情，你无法相信。
And I was so excited to use it.
我很高兴能使用它。
So I'm talking about what it had some of the functionality and also trying to connect my emotion in
所以我说的是它有什么功能，并试图将我的情感联系起来
that time back then to to getting that computer.
那时回到那台电脑。
I played some of those games for hours on end and still feel nostalgic about ski free and M.S. paint
我连续玩了几个小时这些游戏，仍然怀念滑雪免费和 M.S.画
ski free was an as a game where you were a skier and you'd ski down a mountain and then at the end of
自由滑雪是一种游戏，你是一名滑雪者，你会滑雪下山，然后在结束时
a game the this this monster would come out and eat you would always eat you always.
一个游戏，这个怪物会出来吃你总是吃你。
And it was very frustrating and very scary.
这是非常令人沮丧和非常可怕的。
But the game was super fun.
但是游戏超级好玩。
Nostalgia is this feeling of a warm emotion a happy memory connected to something in the past we ever
怀旧是一种温暖情感的感觉，一种与过去我们曾经发生过的事情有关的快乐记忆
had a smell come into your nose and suddenly it brings you back to when you were in high school your
有一种气味进入你的鼻子，突然让你回到高中时的你
first girlfriend or you hear a song and it does the same.
第一个女朋友，或者你听到一首歌，它也是如此。
When I think of MS Paint or I see or I see the ski free monster I am transported back so I feel nostalgic.
当我想到 MS Paint 或者我看到或看到没有滑雪的怪物时，我被带回来了，所以我感到怀旧。
When I was 10 we got a Dell and that computer could connect to the Internet but it was really really
当我 10 岁的时候，我们买了一台戴尔电脑，那台电脑可以连接到互联网，但它真的是
slow.
减缓。
Web pages would take 20 seconds to load and I'd have to use the phone line to connect.
加载网页需要 20 秒，而且我必须使用电话线连接。
You couldn't be on and when I say you couldn't be on.
你不能上当我说你不能上。
This is called the impersonal you.
这被称为非个人的你。
It just means anybody who's doing that.
它只是意味着任何这样做的人。
Anybody who's using the Internet you when you want to succeed in life you have to work hard.
当你想在生活中取得成功时，任何使用互联网的人都必须努力工作。
Maybe I'm just saying that in general to anybody who wants to be successful or may want to be successful.
也许我只是对任何想要成功或可能想要成功的人说一般。
The impersonal you you couldn't be on the phone and using the Internet at the same time.
没有人情味的你，你不能一边打电话一边上网。
So if I was chatting with my friends on a I am which was a very popular chat or messenger at the time.
因此，如果我正在与我的朋友聊天，我是当时非常流行的聊天或信使。
If I was chatting with my friends on a I am sometimes my mom would shout upstairs Hey get off the internet
如果我在和我的朋友聊天，有时我妈妈会在楼上大喊嘿，别上网了
I need to call grandma because I was using the Internet the phone line was blocked because it went over
我需要打电话给奶奶，因为我正在使用互联网电话线被封锁了，因为它超出了
the phone.
电话。
So when my mom needed to make a call she had to ask me to stop looking at my email or whatever so that
所以当我妈妈需要打电话时，她不得不让我停止查看我的电子邮件或其他任何东西
she could make a phone call very primitive.
她可以很原始地打电话。
Right.
正确的。
Very very primitive.
非常非常原始。
Now if I were telling this story more casually with friends I would probably go into even more detail
现在，如果我和朋友更随意地讲述这个故事，我可能会更详细地讲述这个故事
on each point I wanted to give you a simple example so that you could get a feeling and see how I would
在每一点上，我都想给你一个简单的例子，这样你就可以感受一下，看看我会怎么做
connect my emotions nostalgic about this or I was so excited about this how I would connect my emotions
连接我的情绪 怀旧或者我对此感到非常兴奋 我将如何连接我的情绪
to the thing that was happening or the actual object the actual computer or the actual technology right.
对于正在发生的事情或实际对象实际的计算机或实际的技术权利。
So I hope that gives you a clear idea about how we can use some of these words and phrases and also
所以我希望这能让你清楚地了解我们如何使用这些单词和短语，以及
how we can tell a story that's interesting.
我们如何讲一个有趣的故事。
Keeping in mind that if I were telling this story more casually I would say probably much much more.
请记住，如果我更随意地讲述这个故事，我可能会说得更多。
And it would be much more casual I would just speak freely.
我会自由地说话，这会更随意。
I'm writing this down for you so that you can see it.
我写下来给你，让你看。
So now it's time to practice this but I'd like you to do is tell me about the phones that you've owned
所以现在是练习这个的时候了，但我想让你告诉我你拥有的手机
in your lifetime.
在你的一生中。
The phones that you remember throughout your life maybe starting with a landline phone and then moving
您一生都记得的电话可能从固定电话开始，然后移动
to the phone that you own now maybe a smartphone.
到你现在拥有的手机，也许是智能手机。
Talk about the differences between the phones the functionality but also talk about what was going on
谈论手机功能之间的差异，还谈论发生了什么
in your life at the time some of your memories that are connected to that thing.
在你当时的生活中，你的一些记忆与那件事有关。
How did you use it right.
你是如何正确使用它的。
And again try to connect emotion to events and description.
再次尝试将情感与事件和描述联系起来。
Try to use some of the words and phrases that we learned earlier in the class.
尝试使用我们在课堂上早些时候学到的一些单词和短语。
You don't have to use all of them.
您不必全部使用它们。
Certainly I didn't try to use some of them right back then which is an easy one to use.
当然，当时我并没有尝试使用其中的一些，这是一个易于使用的。
Try to use these when you do it and you recorded and then you listen back to it.
尝试在您录制并录制时使用这些，然后再听。
If it's a good story at some point you should smile.
如果在某个时候这是一个好故事，你应该微笑。
If you smile or maybe your mom smiles or your friends smiles when they listen to it then at least you
如果你笑了，或者你妈妈笑了，或者你的朋友听了也笑了，那么至少你
know that you've made something you've done something that is able to move people and that's what stories
知道你已经做了一些你已经做了一些能够打动人们的事情，这就是故事
are all about.
都是关于。
Whether it's a happy story a sad story or just one that is connected to your real emotions in some way.
无论是一个快乐的故事还是一个悲伤的故事，或者只是一个以某种方式与你的真实情绪相关的故事。